

8.5 year's Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Technical Lead, . Net Core, Sql Server, MVC, WebAPI, WCF, Entity Framework, Angular, HTML, CSS, ASP. NET, iQuery, TFS, BitBucket



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: American Infosource Business Solution Pvt. Notice Period: 1 Month

I td.

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science] Current Location: Gurgaon

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System

Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Technical Lead, . Net Core, WebAPI, Sql Server, WCF, MVC, Entity

Framework, Angular, HTML, CSS, ASP. NET, iQuery, JavaScript, TFS, BitBucke

Verified: Phone Number I Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

## Summary

8.4 Year's Experience as software developer. Currently working as Senior Software Engineer in American Infosurce Business Solution.

Developing Web applications using .Net Core, C#.Net, ASP.Net, Ado.Net, SQL Server, MySql, MVC 3.0/4.0/5.0, JQuery, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Ling, Entity Framework, WCF, Web Services, Web API, AngularJS, Angular 8, .Net Core Strong Knowledge of Relational Database Management Systems and C#.

- Strong in backend database development including designing databases, writing stored procedures, functions and triggers for SQL Server and MySQL.
- Experience in Financial Domain bankruptsy services
- Have a good knowledge of Software development life cycle (SDLC)
- Good interpersonal and communication skills and can function very well in a team as well as individually.

# Work Experience

#### American Infosource Business Solution Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer May 2019 to Till Date

Develop, test and implement new software programs. Clearly and regularly communicate with management and technical support colleagues. Test, maintain and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization. Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues. Work with experienced team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, review new and existing code and/or perform unit testing. Identify ideas to improve system performance and impact availability

Incedo Inc as Senior Software Engineer -Dot Net Jun 2017 to Apr 2019

Develop, test and implement new software programs. Clearly and regularly communicate with management and technical support colleagues. Test, maintain and recommend software improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimization. Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues. Work with experienced team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, review new and existing code and/or perform unit testing. Identify ideas to improve system performance and impact availability.

RateGain IT Solutions as Software Engineer Apr 2014 to Jan 2017

Brain Technosys Pvt. Ltd., as Software Developer Jan 2013 to Mar 2014

Max3Logic It Solutions as Trainee Engineer Feb 2012 to Dec 2012

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from shambhunath Institute of engineering and Technology, Allahabad in 2011

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
windows XP/2000/vista/win7	
C#	
MVC, Razor and ASP.NET, HTML	
Angular JS, jQuery, AJAX	
JAVASCRIPT and CSS	
Web Service, WCF, WebAPI	
WINDOW Services	
MS-SQL Server 2008 R2 and 2012	
ADO.NET	
Microsoft .NET framework	
.Net Core	
Entity Framework, Linq, VS Code	
SVN, TFS, BitBucket	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

**Work Authorization** 

Employment Status: Full time